# PENELOPE BRYANT

St. Charles, MO 63303 ◆ 636-448-2091 ◆ penny.bryant@att.net

# PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Accomplished and energetic with a solid history of achievement in higher education. Motivated leader with strong organizational and prioritization abilities. Areas of expertise include management of large groups of individuals, adaptability to an ever changing environment and the ability to take on challenges as they arise.

# **SKILLS**

- Individualized support
- Online Teaching
- Individualized Instruction
- Proficient with Canvas
- Customer Service Oriented
- Able to Adapt Easily to Change

- Research and Analysis
- Lesson Development
- Proficient with Microsoft Products
- Experience with Blackboard and Moodle
- Managed Large Teams

# Work History

# Director, Student and Academic Support Services, 08/2015 to Current

**Lindenwood University** – Saint Charles, MO

- · Serve as contact for LU students to provide academic mentoring, resource referrals, and engagement opportunities.
- · Collect and maintain student documentation.
- · Coordinate and monitor students identified at-risk.
- · Consult with housing, financial aid, business office, faculty, staff and other individuals involved in the student's success and integration.
- · Provide problem resolution options to students considering to exit the university.
- · Plan and develop support programming based on data results.
- · Propose programming or process adjustment based on retention and/or assessment data.
- · Assess current processes and procedures and propose changes to better serve the student community and to improve departmental efficiency.
- · Assist students participating in the at-risk program and those with accommodations to help them learn to manage academics and everyday life.
- · Collect and analyze persistence and retention data for annual report.
- · Hire and interview coordinator and student worker positions within SASS.
- · Supervise and evaluate data-to-day SASS coordinator and student worker performance.
- · Create job proposals, position announcements, and process hiring and access forms for new SASS

coordinator and student worker positions.

- · Development, implementation, and management of sophomore-year experience program
- · Development, implementation, and management the Academic Commitment to Success class .
- · Assess effectiveness of SASS service and student satisfaction.
- · Oversee the office of accessibility efforts to ensure processes are in compliance.
- · Oversee retention efforts and the process of university exits
- · Work collaboratively and establish effective relationships with faculty, students and staff.
- · Strong written and verbal service skills used in academic intervention and outreach.
- · Interpret and follow all FERPA and confidentiality guidelines and explain to students and parents.
- · Participate in appropriate university committees.
- · Provide training to success mentors and coordinators related to student mentoring and office protocol and procedures.

#### **Adjunct Instructor**, 09/2016 to Current

# Lindenwood University - St. Charles, MO

- Academic Commitment to Excellence course for conditionally admitted students (freshmen and transfers). Created and executed the course on Canvas and delivered on ground and online.
- Created and implemented course agendas, lesson plans and activities to successfully meet course objectives.

## **Registrar/Director**, 01/1995 to 06/2015

# St. Louis College of Pharmacy – Saint Louis, MO

- Responsible for all aspects of academic records management in compliance with academic policies/procedures, transfer credit evaluations, commencement and class scheduling.
- Managed the assignment of academic advisors to new students (freshmen and transfers) and dealing with student academic issues.
- Planned and organized comprehensive programs in recruitment and admissions.
- Responsibilities included: Train and supervise the Admissions/Registrar staff.
- Plan, organize and implement an effective record maintenance system.
- Manage recruitment strategies to meet annual enrollment goals and make recommendations for changes or suggest new processes to meet the demands of an ever-changing student market.
- Prepare course schedules for each term and for final exams.
- Supervise the distribution of midterm and final grades, distribution lists, and supervised enrollment certifications and verification and transcript requests.
- Responsible for all outside reporting (i.e.
- IPEDS, US News and World Report, Wintergreen, Petersons).
- Manage the preparation and verification of academic disciplinary student lists at the end of each semester and degree audits for all students used in advising.
- Supervise pre-registration programs and commencement.
- Manage the admission acceptance process for freshmen.
- Supervise a complex computer system for registration and curriculum control.

- Scheduled courses to meet all demands (i.e.
- Instructor availability, instructor requests for time and location preferences, room/lab sizes, and availability for specific courses across the curriculum).
- Act as an advisor to undergraduate and graduate students.

#### **Adjunct Instructor**, 08/2007 to 05/2009

# St. Louis College of Pharmacy – Saint Louis, MO

- Professional communication course taught to upper level undergraduate students.
- Topics covered included interpersonal and non-verbal communications and public speaking.
- Students were expected to be prepared to role play various scenario's involving interactions with patients in the health care field.

#### **Adjunct Instructor**, 09/1995 to 12/1995

## **Lindenwood College** – Saint Charles, MO

• Used lectures, discussions and demonstrations to increase learning and classroom success.

## **Assistant Registrar**, 04/1991 to 12/1994

#### **Lindenwood College** – Saint Charles, MO

• Responsibilities included computer system management, campus system reports, IPEDS reporting, probation/suspension reports, graduation certification, grade reports, transcript evaluations, registration and student advising.

#### Alumni Relations Coordinator, 08/1989 to 04/1991

#### **Lindenwood College** – Saint Charles, MO

- Responsibilities included alumni correspondence, giving, activities and publications.
- Maintained a volunteer pool of 75 alumni to work on events, with 35 alumni very active in all College sponsored activities.

## EDUCATION -

Master of Science: Management and Administration

**Lindenwood University - St. Charles, MO** 

**Bachelor of Science**: Mass Communications **Lindenwood University** - St. Charles, MO

**Ed.S.**: Educational Technology, Expected in 12/2021 **University of Missouri, Columbia -** Columbia, MO